# Umut Seven | Curriculum Vitæ

Bristol, UK

→ +44 (736) 682 3919
→ umutseven92@gmail.com
→ https://umutseven.com
→ github.com/umutseven92

# **Summary**

Over 9 years of experience as a Full Stack Software Engineer with a focus on APIs and Microservices. Experienced in building reliable & scalable systems, from Web and Mobile apps, to Backend Services that serve millions of users.

M.S. in Software Engineering from Boğaziçi University.

- Languages: Python, Rust, Dart, C#, Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, F#, C, Prolog
- Frameworks: Django, Flask, FastAPI, Flutter, Svelte, .NET, Spring
- Cloud: AWS, GCP, Firebase
- DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform
- Other: Elasticsearch, Lucene, Kafka

# **Professional Experience**

Sunbeam Bristol, UK

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2024 - Present

Jun 2021 - Jul 2024

Python, FastAPI, Terraform

AWS

As an early engineer at Sunbeam, I contribute to the development of our feedback analytics system.

Cookpad Bristol, UK

Lead Engineer

Python, FastAPI, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Kubernetes, Terraform

Δ\Λ/S

As the Lead Engineer for the Search Team, I collaborated with Product Managers to spearhead the development of new features, address technical debt, and oversee the software development cycle. In addition to my core duties as a Search Engineer, I led a diverse team of over 10 engineers, ensuring an exceptional search experience for our users.

Cookpad Bristol, UK

Search Engineer Jan 2021 – Jun 2021

Python, FastAPI, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Kubernetes, Terraform

AWS

Helped develop the various search systems for Cookpad, including APIs, an ETL pipeline and Elasticsearch, improved search quality by collaboration with our Country Managers and tuning relevance. Helped build the Search infrastructure, using tools like Terraform and Kubernetes.

Cookpad Bristol, UK

Full Stack Engineer

Mar 2019 - Jan 2021

Flutter, Dart, Python, Django, Svelte, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Firebase, GCP

As a solo developer working on a greenfield project for a skunkworks team, developed both the Android and iOS apps using Flutter & Dart, a customer facing web app via Svelte, REST API via Django, and the infrastructure powering all of it, using Firebase tools like Cloud Firestore, Firebase Cloud Messaging and Firebase Cloud Functions.

## 4play Digital Workshop

Istanbul, Turkey

Software Developer

Sep 2018- Feb 2019

Java, Spring, RabbitMQ

Developed web services and miscellaneous VAS services for mobile operators. Designed & implemented agile software development methodologies for the development team.

Armut Istanbul, Turkey

Software Developer

Feb 2018- Aug 2018

C#, .NET, JavaScript, HTML, CSS



Developed both the front-end and the back-end services of <u>armut.com</u>, leveraging multiple AWS products to deploy and monitor services. Implemented the CI/CD pipeline for multiple microservices.

P.I. Works Istanbul, Turkey

Software Developer

Sep 2015-Feb 2018

C#, .NET, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Developed multiple real-time software projects that optimize & profile mobile base stations, making the mobile operators more efficient and less error prone. Designed and developed customized DevOps tools for the engineering team.

P.I. Works Istanbul, Turkey

Software Development Intern

Jul 2014-Sep 2014

C#, .NET, JavaScript, Python

Developed web & desktop based performance monitoring and reporting tools. Improved the CI/CD process.

#### Education

## Boğaziçi University

Istanbul, Turkey

Software Engineering, MS

2017-2019

Papers:

- Survey of Android Malware Detection
- Survey of Software Bug Prediction
- TCP Vegas: End to End Congestion Avoidance on a Global Internet
- Automatic Trailer Generation for Movies

#### **Istanbul University**

Istanbul, Turkey

Business Administration, BBA

2010–2015

# **Selected Personal Projects**

#### apyr

Python, FastAPI

apyr (all lowercase) is a simple & easy to use mock API server. Great for front-end development when your API is not ready, or when you are prototyping an API- also very useful for demos & hackathon!

https://github.com/umutseven92/apyr

#### LaFontaine

Python, NLTK

LaFontaine is an automatic movie trailer generator. LaFontaine creates movie trailers for any genre using pre-defined features, like number of faces on screen, and loudness of volume. Scenes are extracted using these features and combined to create the final trailer. There are three features for frame, three features for sound and three features for subtitles. Features are read from configurations and are fully configurable.

https://github.com/umutseven92/LaFontaine

#### **Shorts Blocker**

CSS, Chrome Extension

Shorts Blocker is a simple Chrome extension that blocks YouTube shorts, using CSS injection. Also available in the <a href="Chrome Web Store">Chrome Web Store</a>.

• https://github.com/umutseven92/shorts-blocker

## Godspeed

Lua, Playdate

Godspeed is a simple game for Playdate, inspired by the movie Speed. You play as a bus, speeding down a highway full of obstacles, and if you slow down, or crash too much, the bomb explodes. Also available on itch.io.

https://github.com/umutseven92/godspeed

{ This isn't all! See more at github.com/umutseven92. }

# **Certifications & Training**

#### Qualifications

Microsoft Certified Professional (MC ID: 10495811)

#### **Certificates**

- Microsoft Certified Professional Certificate (E498-2569)
- Programming in C# Specialist Certificate (E498-2567)

#### **Training**

• Think Like A Relevance Engineer - Elasticsearch by OpenSource Connections

## Miscellaneous

Other: Fluent in English (IELTS Score of 8.5, both Academic and General)

{ This CV is also on GitHub! Check it out at github.com/umutseven92/CV. }